nerdtechy.com 2019-12-13

# Privacy Policy - Nerd Techy

### Effective from May 20th, 2018

### Who we are

NerdTechy.com respects the privacy of every individual who visits www.nerdtechy.com (“Website”) and/or uses its Services. This Privacy Policy is our commitment to transparency in communicating how we collects, uses, and discloses the information that is collected from you, the visitor of its website and/or customer as well as the choices you have with respect to the information.

Our privacy policy has been written in layman’s terms and simplified to be a concise, truthful and accurate. This policy outlines what personal data we collect and why we collect it.

### Comments

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

### Contact Form

When you send us a message through our contact form, we ask for your email address and name. This information is not used for marketing purposes and is simply used for replying to any request that you may have. We do not store this information.

### Media

If you upload images to this website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website. We currently do not have any way for you to upload images.

### Cookies

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

We do not have a registration form so we will not ask for your name, email or any other contact information unless you’re leaving a comment in reply to one of our articles.

### Embedded content from other websites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

### Analytics

In order to understand where our visitors are coming from and how many users visit our website each day, month, year, etc. we use software called Google Analytics and Matomo. This software gives us your IP address and some generalized Geo-IP information. Your IP address is anonymized for added security and anonymity. For example, rather than a specific IP like 192.168.100.200, your IP is viewed as 192.168.XXX.XXX. For more information, please view [Google’s Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/analytics/terms/us.html) as well as [Matomo’s Privacy Policy](https://matomo.org/privacy-policy/).

### Who we share your data with

We do not share your data with any third parties unless specified.

### How long we retain your data

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

### What rights you have over your data

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

### Where we send your data

Your data is not sent to anyone but simply stored within a database on our LiquidWeb server. Take a look at [LiquidWeb’s Privacy Policy](https://www.liquidweb.com/about-us/policies/privacy-policy/) for more information.

Please understand that visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service. This helps cut-down on incoming spam and keeps comments relevant.

### How we protect your data

We keep your data protected by utilizing up-to-date encryption services provided by our WebHost, LiquidWeb. All of your stored data is actively monitored for breaches and kept safely away from hackers or potential threats.

### What data breach procedures we have in place

If for any reason at anytime your information is breached, we will promptly notify our website visitors within 15 days. This will be done via email to those who have left comments on our website since this is the only way we have to contact you as we do not collect anything more than anonymized IP addresses, names and email addresses.

### Changes to our Privacy Policy

We keep our privacy policy under regular review and we will place any updates on this website. This privacy policy was last updated on May 20th, 2018.

### Contact information

If you need to contact us, please use our [contact form](https://nerdtechy.com/contact) or send an email to NerdTechy321(AT)gmail.com.

### Opt-out of Matomo Analytic Software tracking
